Richard George Heck

whattherichard.github.io linkedin.com/in/hecktech

Indianapolis, IN (317) 460-6310 whatthegeorge@gmail.com

Looking at things from many perspectives, my analytical mind enjoys problem solving. I am focusing that talent on translating business needs into effective online engagement. Being enthusiastically engaged in discovering technologies that enrich lives, I am passionate about the future of technology and the community it can create.

My background has been in leadership and customer service with a recent swing into web developing and different development management techniques. Previous jobs and training have taught me how to encourage and motivate individuals to work effectively as a team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed (August 2017 - Present)

JavaScript Developer/Online Presence Consultant - work with both private and public sectors; advise and assist in
design and platform for online engagement, implementation of various technologies utilizing data tracking and predictive
analytics; using Node.js, Angular, SQL, React, Express, and other tools to create custom content

Brad Osborne Real Estate P.C. (2017 - 2018)

- Personal Assistant organized and maintained office filing system; assisted with finances and project management; daily check in and updates; streamlined processes and created system of prioritization for daily tasks ensuring efficiency Ransburg Scout Reservation (Summer 2014, 2016)
 - High Adventure Instructor and Certified COPE Director lived on campgrounds through summer instructing and leading Scouts through the Climbing Merit Badge and COPE (challenge obstacle course)
 - Volunteered weekly and taught "Climb On Safely" course to adult troop leaders

Ed Martin Acura (2015 - 2016)

• Detailer/Lot Assistant/Porter - Self-managed tasks; cleaned and detailed cars; valet of vehicles; seasonal showroom arrangement; maintaining front and back stock lots; pick up and drop-off customers

REGO-Fix (2013 - 2014)

• Warehouse Technician - Re-categorized warehouse inventory with new database system increasing productivity and efficiency 50%, allowing for promotions

Byron Fellowship (2011 - 2013)

Director of Communications - Coordinated nominee application and screening process, assisted in preparing attendees
and instructors for course work, management of online profiles and accommodations; assisted and participated in
implementation of course sessions; established social media presence on Facebook, LinkedIn, and Twitter; established
Salesforce application setup and email protocols; maintained website

NOTE: Gaps in employment were filled with various restaurant positions focused in customer service and sales

CERTIFICATES

Minister - American Marriage Ministries (2017)

COPE Director - National Camp School (2014)

- · Became proficient leading groups safely through teambuilding obstacles, facilitating personal and team development
- Mastered the ability to safely instruct and operate an outdoor artificial climbing facility

Byron Fellow - Byron Fellowship (2011)

- Focus on Sustainability and Leadership; place-based learning, with the evolution of group structures and communities 1st Dan Black Belt North Indy Taekwondo (2008 2014)
 - Learned patience, discipline and self-control; assisted in instructing lower belt levels

COMMUNITY ACTIVITIES

City of Carmel (2006 - present)

- Assisted with the setup, implementation and takedown of large-scale community events including Holiday on the Square, Carmelfest, International Arts Festival and Jazz on the Monon
- Assisted in production of various government cable channel programs
- Video talent for Artomobilia, Jazz on the Monon and Carmel Teen Police Academy

EDUCATION

Eleven Fifty Academy, JavaScript 151- 8 week, JavaScript 201- 1 week, JavaScript 301- 1 week (2017)

• Built multiple Full-Stack web applications using Node.js, GitHub, SQL, jQuery, Angular, React/Redux, HTML/CSS with extensive manual testing and de-bugging; built a portfolio; became skilled in Agile fundamentals and public speaking

Ivy Tech Community College, General Studies (2011 - 2014)

Focused on Economics and Philosophy

Carmel High School, Core 40 (2011)

Pre-law college courses